

# Anbo CAO

Master of mechanical engineering, dual degree in China and France.

24 years old | +86 15600110889 | Anbo19950829@sjtu.edu.cn

### **Education**

2017.9-present Shanghai Jiao Tong University Mechanical Engineering, M.D.

GPA: 4.0/4.0

Major courses: finite element analysis, structural mechanics, multi-scale simulation of nano-systems, fatigue and fracture mechanics, rupture mechanics, fluid-structure interaction, etc.

2016.9-present ENSTA ParisTech Mechanical Engineering, M.D.

2013.9-2017.9 Shanghai Jiao Tong University Mechanical Engineering, B.D.

# Research experience

#### 2019.4-present Shanghai Jiao Tong University

Superlubricity on Graphene Induced by Mussel Adhesive Protein Interlayer Project description: Mussel adhesive protein interlayer is prepared on SiO2 substrate by immersing the substrate in protein solution. Superlubricity is observed when graphene is put on this protein coating.

### 2018.9-2019.4 Shanghai Jiao Tong Univerisity

Influence of Stone-Wales Defect on Graphene Friction: Pinning Effect and Wrinkle Modication Project description: The influence of Stone-Wales defect on the friction characteristics of graphene is studied by molecular dynamics simulation. The simulations are done in LAMMPS and the simulation data is analyzed by Python.

The paper of this project is under peer review.

#### 2018.3-2018.7 CNRS / Institut Neel (NEEL)

Thermal Stability and Crystal Orientation of Sputtered Platinum Films on Different Substrates Project description: Platinum films are prepared on MgO, Al2O3 and other substrates by sputtering deposition. The samples are annealed and characterized by AFM, XRD and XRR.

## **Summary**

Fluent in Chinese, English and French. My TOFEL score is 113 and my GRE grade is 330+3.5. My TCF rank is C1. Mastering programming languages such as Python and MATLAB. Experience in LAMMPS, VMD, Ansys, HyperWorks, COMSOL and Solidworks.